Remember I took some personal leave?
还记得我那几天因私休假了吗
My daughter was born 10 weeks prematurely.
我女儿早产10周
That's when Karl Frierson brought you in.
就是那个时候 Karl Frierson让你参与进来
You see, I've been taking another look at it.
我回过头来重新想了想
And it seems to me that you and Frierson dropped
看起来像是你和Frierson
every lead I had uncovered straight down the toilet,
把每一个我没有找到的线索
till it went cold.
都清理的干干净净
Is that an accusation?
这是指控吗
No, no, no. That's an observation.
不不不 是我的观察
So tell me, Jim,
告诉我 Jim
why did you roll over for Karl Frierson?
你为什么要接替Karl Frierson
The race hasn't finished yet, Jim.
Jim 比赛还没结束呢
Our horse is gonna win.
我们下注的马会赢的
Every time I followed something,
每次我查到一些线索
he blocked it.
他就阻止
There was a suspect.
曾经有个嫌疑犯
We waited too long. He disappeared.
我们等了很久 可他消失了
Frierson wanted to kill it?
Frierson想让证据消失
Nothing I could prove.
我找不到证据
If I were you, I'd let it go, Harry.
Harry 如果我是你 我会放手的
He's a very powerful man,
他很有势力
and he always gets what he wants.
他可以为所欲为
Forget her past
忘记她的过去胜出了
You let a murderer go, Jim.
Jim 你放跑了一个杀人犯
I did wanna say thank you
我真得好好谢谢你
for the way you've treated me these last few days.
感谢你过去这几天的款待
I'll remember it.
我会记住的
And give my regards to your wife and daughter...
带我问候你太太和女儿
Anna and Daisy, isn't it?
Anna和Daisy 对吗
Harry?
Harry
CPS didn't think we had enough
CPS认为我们没有足够的证据
evidence to make the charges stick.
证明对她的指控
But that's shite!
都是屁话
We have Lily-Anne's memory stick.
我们有Lily-Anne的记忆棒
It clearly shows that Tim Larson
上面清楚地显示了Tim Larson
owed Lily-Anne 110,000 Pounds.
欠了她11万英镑
As you know, Tim Larson's still
你得知道 Tim Larson
maintaining that he killed Caleb Pursey
还顶着杀死Caleb Pursey的罪名
because he owed him money and
因为Caleb Pursey欠了他钱
Pursey's threatened his family.
还威胁了他的家人
He's lying!
他在说谎
We need a conviction on this.
我们需要让人信服的证据
And that's what we're gonna get
所以我们得盯着Tim Larson
with Tim Larson, not Lily-Anne Lau.
而不是Lily-Anne Lau
We got into this to go after the bad guys.
我们办案是为了抓坏人的
Do you remember?
你还记得吗
So, everything we have to work per today is simple.
我们每天要做的事情都很简单
It's really easy to grasp.
非常容易掌握
There's questions of your responsibility and community.
问一个关于你们的责任和社区关系的问题
Jake,
Jake
can you tell me what you think's
能告诉我你认为
gonna be the most difficult thing
在你出狱后
to achieve when you're released?
哪件事情是最难完成的
Well, I guess this community thing
我觉得这些社区的东西
sounds like a bit of shit.
听上去屁用都没有
Harry, it's me.
Harry 是我
Still no luck finding anyone who's heard of Marghai.
还是没有发现任何听说过Marghai的人
Call me when you get this, please.
听到消息请回电
Hey.
你好
No, no, no. You can't come back here, Harry!
Harry 你不能进来
Lily-Anne's been released.
Lily-Anne被释放了
But you knew that already.
可是你早已经知道了
How would I know that, Harry?
Harry 我怎么可能知道
Because you are the sewer through which she contacts me.
因为你就是她联系我的线人
You know you look a little stressed.
你看起来压力有些大
Can I get you a drink?
想喝一杯吗
You want some mint tea?
来点薄荷茶
That bitch threatened my family.
那个贱人威胁了我的家人
Now I want you to get her a message from me.
我现在要你代我给她传个信
If she ever goes near my family,
她胆敢靠近我的家人
I will find her
我会找到她
and I will finish her.
亲手了结她
Harry,
Harry
you're a detective. Man of the law.
你是个警察  是法律的守护者
You know you don't mean that.
你是在说笑
Tell her.
告诉她
Make her understand.
让她明白
No-one comes near my family!
没人能靠近我的家人
Hi, Billy?
Billy
Do you remember me?
记得我吗
I spoke to you last week.
我上周和你谈过
We were talking about Kevin Grey?
我们谈了Kevin Grey
Please lady?
女士 行行好
Leave me alone!
离我远点
I think you know how he died.
我认为你知道他的死因
Golding.
Golding
It was Golding.
是Golding干的
See you and Frierson are friends again, Alistair.
Alistair 你和Frierson又和好啦
Smashing stuff!
太赞了
What are you doing here, Harry?
Harry 你来这儿干什么
Oh I just wanted the heads-up on
我就是想来听听治理
the new crime initiative for our city.
我们城市犯罪活动的新点子
Reclaim the neighbourhood.
社区改造
What does that mean exactly?
那是个什么意思
Means we're not longer on the back foot to crime.
意思是面对犯罪活动 我们不再处于下风了
Brilliant! London can sleep easily.
太好了 伦敦不会有不眠夜了
Don't you get tired of playing the idiot?
你这么装傻不累吗
Well, soon I'll get tired.
很快会累的
So why don't you stop?
那你干嘛不停下
Go save your marriage.
去拯救你的婚姻吧
Be a better dad.
做个好父亲
Stop gambling. Do nice things.
戒赌 做善事
Why did you never get married, Alistair?
Alistair 你为什么不结婚
I forgot.
我想起来了
You found the greatest love.
你找到了至高无上的爱
It's always troubled you, hasn't it, Harry?
Harry 我从我的信仰中汲取力量
That I draw so much strength from my faith.
这事儿很困扰你吗
Or is it I've found something more to believe in
或者说是我找到了更能让我相信的东西
And you so obviously haven't.
而你显然没有
Guests! Can we put our hands together for our speaker?
来宾们 掌声欢迎我们的演讲者
The deputy mayor, Karl Frierson.
副市长Karl Frierson
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome
女士们 先生们 欢迎各位
and thank you for your presence here,
感谢出席本次
at the launch of my new initiative
由我发起的
Reclaim the neighbourhood.
重塑社区活动
But first, a little of who I am
首先 简单向大家介绍我是谁
and what London means to me.
以及伦敦对我的意义
I was a policeman for 20 years before I got very sick.
我从警20年 直到一场大病袭来
It was a year ago, February the 15th,
那是多年前的2月15日
and I was in a bed at the Cardwell clinic,
我躺在Cardwell诊所的病床上
dying.
濒临死亡
My doctor said that
我的医生说
all my options had been exhausted.
我所有的救治希望都已破灭
What was wrong?
他得了什么病
Chronic kidney failure.
慢性肾衰竭
...but, February the 15th was no ordinary day.
但2月15日 是个不同寻常的日子
Against all odds,
all expectations,
出乎所有人意料
a donor was found and
一位捐助者出现了
my life was saved.
我得救了
And I knew that I'd been given a chance
老天给了我一次机会
not just to live again
不仅是为了重生
but to live in a way that I wanted to live,
而是以我想要的方式在这个
in the city that I love.
我爱的城市里重生
I've spent most of today looking for a Sierra Leonean
今天我花了很长时间寻找一家名叫
aid agency called African Health Union?
非洲健康联盟的塞拉利昂救助机构
It has a base here.
它的总部在这个位置
I'm sorry, I've never heard of it.
抱歉 我从未听说过这家机构
And I know nearly all the
我听说过几乎所有
West African aid agencies around here.
这附近的西非救助机构
What about a doctor Marghai?
Marghai医生呢
You've heard of a doctor Marghai?
你听说过这个人吗
No. I've never heard of him.
没有 从没有听说过
Is there somewhere else we can talk?
有没有可以私聊的地方
It is very important we find him.
我们得找到这个人 这很重要
He might be involved in a brutal murder
他可能涉及一起残忍杀害
of a member of your community.
你社区同胞的凶杀案件
I think the charity you're looking for
你要找的慈善组织
no longer exists.
已经不存在了
This fact sheet may help.
这张证明可能会对你有用
Anna.
Anna
Harry!
Harry
I didn't know you were here.
没想到你会来
No, I wasn't invited. I crashed this party.
没人邀请我 我闯进来的
Harry, this is Nikhail Julian,
Harry 这位是Nikhail Julian
the governor of White Cross prison.
白色十字监狱的狱长
Nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你
This is Harry Clayton.
这位是Harry Clayton
We were just talking about Anna signing up
我们刚刚正说到Anna已经签约
to be a mentor in the prison's outreach program.
成为我们监狱拓展项目的导师
Nikhail! The outreach program!
Nikhail 拓展项目
Amazing project, incredible results!
是个了不起的项目 给社会带来了意想不到的结果
Glad we backed you on this one.
很高兴在这个项目上我们提供了支持
We know each other, don't we?
我们认识吗
Yeah! Indeed. I'm Harry Clayton.
是的 我是Harry Clayton
We worked together...
很多年前
many years ago.
我们共事过
You were the Senior Investigating
那时您是在MIA负责我
Officer on my first case at MIA's.
第一个案子的调查主任
Right.
这样
It was the murder of... Maria Alexandri.
那是Maria Alexandri的凶杀案
It was never solved.
还没有结案
Afraid I don't remember it.
恐怕我不记得了
That way you've done great things since.
那您可是帮了我们大忙
And terrific speech by the way!
顺便说一下 讲的很精彩